hey what's up guys my name is Aero and
welcome back to my C++ Series so you've
decided to use a
Mac there are plenty of different tools
you can use to build C++ applications on
Mac but the one that I'm going to
recommend is xcode xcode is an ID
written by Apple it's not too bad it can
be slow on large projects for example we
use xcode over at EA to build games for
iOS and I can tell you that some of the
compil times are upwards of 20 minutes
for games like Need for Speed No Limits
it's also a nightmare to actually write
code because everything's lagging like
crazy when you've got a project that
large however for small projects like
this and to learn C++ I still think
xcode is probably the best IDE so let's
go ahead and install it okay so on your
Mac we're going to go to the App Store
we're going to type in
xcode and then we're going to install it
and of course this will take some time
depending on how fast your internet is
is all right so once X code is installed
let's go ahead and open it we'll accept
all of the terms and
conditions xcode's going to go ahead and
install some components for us okay so
once that's done we're going to create a
new xcode project for the template we're
just going to click on Mac OS and then
choose command line tool we'll give it a
name so hello world in this case and
then under the language we're going to
select C++ you'll have to put in some
kind of organization identifier like
com. your comp's the suggested one so
you can do something like com do
whatever domain name you own it doesn't
really matter this is just supposed to
be some kind of unique identifier it
doesn't really matter what it is um just
put something in there and hit
next then you're going to want to select
a location for this um I like to store
things inside my user directory and then
in a folder called Dev so I'll make a
folder called Dev and then just click
create in there all right so there we go
xcode would like to access your contacts
we don't really need that for this um
this this is basically what an xcode
project looks like there's a few project
settings that you'll find inside the
actual if you click on the actual name
of the project you've got all these
build settings and build phases for the
most part we don't really need to touch
anything so you'll see that we've Al
we've already got a main. CPP file and
we've already got a bunch of code but
I'm going to type it out again just so
that it matches the other videos so
basically we're going to do include IO
stream int
main stdc out hello
world
and then we'll do our
STD cin.get
save that and then all you have to do to
actually build it is you can hit product
and then
build that will compile it for you there
you go build succeeded and then if you
want to run it you can just hit this
play button that will also build it as
well you'll have to enable developer
mode if this is your first time running
xcode and off we go so the build
succeeded and you should see a console
pop out in the bottom here with your
output we'll just hit enter and you can
see the program terminates successfully
and that's it we're ready to learn C++
on Mac all right you've got xcode up and
running you're finally ready to learn
some C++ over the next few videos we're
going to start learning how C++ actually
works because that's pretty much the key
to writing it properly until then make
sure you follow me on Twitter and
Instagram and if you really like this
series you can support it on patreon
well I'll see you guys next time goodbye